YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 3. National Administrative Office
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. GENERAL ADMINISTRATION
  - National Office/National Staff
    - Union
      - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and agreements, 1949-59 (Box 157, Folder 3-11)
      - National Board Negotiating Committee: minutes
        - 1952 (Box 157, Folder 12)
        - 1956-57 (Box 158, Folder 1)
      - Notes and research materials, 1956-57 (Box 158, Folder 2-3)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and agreements, 1960-67 (Box 158, Folder 4-5)
      - Notes and research materials, 1964-67 (Box 158, Folder 6-7)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and agreements, 1969-70 (Box 158, Folder 8)
      - Notes and research materials, 1971-73 (Box 158, Folder 9-10)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and agreements, 1973-99, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 1-6)
  - Organizations
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-99 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Cooperation/Steering Committee on Cooperation: minutes, reports, and correspondence, 1939-53, 1955-66 (Box 160, Folder 2-9)
    - National Volunteer Issues Leadership Meeting, 1990 (Box 160, Folder 10)
    - Avon Products, Inc., 1994-99 (Box 160, Folder 11)
    - Bishop Desmond Tutu Southern African Refugee Scholarship Fund, 1985-91 (Box 160, Folder 12)
    - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1979 (Box 160, Folder 13)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (aka Filer Commission), 1973-76 (Box 160, Folder 14)
    - Girls Incorporated, 1996-2000, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Interchurch World Movement
      - General and General Committee, 1918-20 (Box 161, Folder 2-3)
      - Cabinet, 1919-20 (Box 161, Folder 4-7)
      - Executive Committee, 1919-20 (Box 161, Folder 8-9)
    - Licensed Agencies for Relief in Asia (LARA): 50th Anniversary scrapbook, 1996 (Box 161, Folder 10)
    - Ms. Foundation for Women, 1994 (Box 161, Folder 11)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare, 1978-79 (Box 161, Folder 12)
    - Soviet Women's Committee
      - Trips, 1985-87 (Box 161, Folder 13-15)
      - Rockefeller Foundation Report, 1986-89 (Box 161, Folder 16)
    - Traveler's Aid, 1913 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - United Service Organizations, Inc., 1961-79 (Box 162, Folder 2-12)
    - United Way (Box 163)
      - General, 1976-89 (Box 163, Folder 1)
      - Long Range Planning Report, 1979 (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - Women's Action Alliance, 1979 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Youth Service America and National Youth Service Day, 1997-2001 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Zonta International, 1999 (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - World's YWCA
      - General and History
        - Miscellaneous, 1909-99, n.d. (Box 164, Folder 1-2)
        - Constitution revisions, 1947-72 (Box 164, Folder 3)
        - Consultant on Buildings (Josephine Ainsworth), 1961-62 (Box 164, Folder 4)
        - Consultations
          - Teaching of Foreign Languages in Voluntary Organizations, 1963-64 (Box 164, Folder 5)
          - Vocational Training, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 6)
          - Women: A Power for Change, sponsored by YWCA of the U.S.A., autumn, 1974 (Box 164, Folder 7)
          - Structural Adjustment, 1994 (Box 164, Folder 8)
        - International Training Institute, 1994 (Box 164, Folder 9)
        - Interns, 1996-98 (Box 164, Folder 10)
        - Nominations for World leadership, 1995-99 (Box 164, Folder 11)
        - NGO Information Seminar on Disarmament, 1965-66 (Box 164, Folder 12)
        - Pension Study, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 13)
        - Study Group on the Role of Youth Promoting Youth Participation in National and World Development, 1968-69 (Box 164, Folder 14)
        - Trainee Program, 1965-70 (Box 164, Folder 15)
        - UN Women's Conference and NGO Forum Regional Meeting, World YWCA team, 1994 (Box 164, Folder 16)
        - Vietnam refugees, 1965-66 (Box 164, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence
        - 1957-63 (Box 164, Folder 18-22)
        - 1964-72, 1994-99 (Box 165, Folder 1-10)
      - Council Meetings
        - 1955 (Box 165, Folder 11)
        - 1967 (Box 165, Folder 12)
        - 1987 (held in U.S.A. at Leadership Development Center) (Box 165)
          - Attendees (Box 165, Folder 13)
          - Budget and fund raising (Box 165, Folder 14)
          - Clippings and publicity (Box 165, Folder 15)
          - Committees (Box 166, Folder 1-4)
          - Correspondence (Box 166, Folder 5)
          - Evaluations (Box 166, Folder 6)
          - Information Letter (Box 166, Folder 7)
          - Peace Site dedication (Box 166, Folder 8)
          - Phoenix Forum (Box 166, Folder 9)
          - Planning and logistics (Box 166, Folder 10)
          - Post-Council Visits Programme
            - General (Box 166, Folder 11)
            - Applications and resource materials (Box 166, Folder 12)
            - Clippings and final reporting (Box 166, Folder 13)
            - Participants and itineraries (Box 166, Folder 14)
          - Programs and schedules (Box 166, Folder 15)
          - U.S.A. Delegates Briefing packet, Jun 1986 (Box 166, Folder 16)
        - 1995 (Box 167, Folder 1)
        - 1999
          - Delegate applications (Box 167, Folder 2-3)
          - Slate of delegates (Box 167, Folder 4)
          - Pre-Council materials (Box 167, Folder 5)
          - Programs and schedules (Box 167, Folder 6)
          - Reports and other post-council materials (Box 167, Folder 7)
      - Financial
        - General, 1943-55, 1995-99 (Box 167, Folder 8-12)
        - International Building Fund, 1995-98 (Box 167, Folder 13)
      - Reports, 1958-70, 1999 (Box 167, Folder 14-17)
      - World's Alliance of Young Men's Christian Associations Relationship, 1947-56 (Box 168, Folder 1-4)
    - Young Men's Christian Association
      - General and History
        - YMCA history, 1916-2000, n.d. (Box 169, Folder 1)
        - Index to chronological file, 1926-54 (Box 169, Folder 2)
        - Chronological file
          - 1907, 1926-55 (Box 169, Folder 3-11)
          - 1956-64 (Box 170, Folder 1-11)
          - 1965-2000, n.d. (Box 171, Folder 1-11)
        - Building and Furnishing Services (YMCA), 1953-59 (Box 172, Folder 1)
      - Committees/Commissions
        - Inter-Association Council on Small Cities and Towns, 1925-26 (Box 172, Folder 2)
        - Commission to Study Relationships with the YMCA/on Cooperation with the YMCA, 1925-30 (Box 172, Folder 3)
        - YWCA and YMCA National Commissions on Cooperation
          - Minutes, 1925-29 (Box 172, Folder 4)
          - Reports
            - Synopsis of Case Histories of YMCA and YWCA Relationships, Mar 1926 (Box 172, Folder 5)
            - Colored Work Case Histories (Box 172, Folder 6)
            - State Case Histories (Box 172, Folder 7)
            - Rural (Town and Country) Case Histories (Box 172, Folder 8)
            - Town (Small City) Case Histories (Box 172, Folder 9)
        - Council on Work Relations with the YMCA, 1930-31 (Box 172, Folder 10)
        - National YWCA-YMCA Consultative Committee: pamphlet "Working Together with Teen-Age Youth: Some Guiding Principles for YMCA-YWCA Cooperation," 1948 (Box 172, Folder 11)
        - Task Force on YMCA-YWCA Relationships/Task Force of the National YMCA and YWCA, 1971-74 (Box 172, Folder 12-15)
        - Special Task Group on Relationships of YMCAs to YWCAs in Local Situations, 1977 (Box 172, Folder 16)
      - Community Associations
        - Statistics, 1955-58 (Box 172, Folder 17)
        - General, 1965-68 (Box 172, Folder 18)
        - Colorado Springs, 1967-68 (Box 172, Folder 19)
        - Iowa, 1965-68 (Box 172, Folder 20)
        - New York City, 1966-67 (Box 172, Folder 21)
      - Publications
        - "Administration of Shared Facilities," work tool, 1961 (Box 173, Folder 1)
        - Co-operation Between the Young Women's and Young Men's Christian Associations by J. Quincy Ames, circa 1930. Monograph no. VIII of "The Changing Young Men's Christian Association" Series (Box 173, Folder 2)
        - "YMCA-YWCA Cooperation," work tool prepared by the Community Division, 1956 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - Studies
        - Reconnaissance Study YMCA-YWCA Relations in the Field in the United States of America by Herbert N. Shenton and Earl S. Eubank, 1930 (Box 173)
          - Clippings (Box 173, Folder 4)
          - Full report [no photocopying] (Box 173, Folder 5)
          - Photocopy of text (without charts and enclosures) (Box 174, Folder 1)
        - A Study of YMCA Constituency After One Hundred Years, YMCA Bureau of Records, Studies and Trends, 1942 (Box 174, Folder 2)
        - Women and Girls in the Young Men's Christian Association: A Study of Current Practices, YMCA Bureau of Records, Studies, and Trends, 1946 (Box 174, Folder 3)
        - Women in the YMCA Record, YMCA National Council Study, 1947 (Box 174, Folder 4)
        - YMCA and YWCA Relationships in Joint Use of Buildings, YMCA Research, Studies and Records Department, 1959 (Box 174, Folder 5)
        - "The Role of the YWCA in a Changing Era: The YWCA Study of YMCA-YWCA Cooperative Experiences" by Dan W. Dodson, 1960
          - Correspondence, questionnaire, press releases, 1958-66 (Box 174, Folder 6-8)
          - Preliminary draft, Aug 1960 (Box 174, Folder 9)
          - Final report, Nov 1960 (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - YWCAs, National-other countries
      - Correspondence
        - Miscellaneous, 1967-74, 1994-97, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 1)
        - Australia, 1971-97 (Box 175, Folder 2)
        - Canada, 1972-2002 (Box 175, Folder 3)
        - China, 1980, 1991-95 (Box 175, Folder 4)
        - El Salvador, 1991 (Box 175, Folder 5)
        - Fiji, 1969-94 (Box 175, Folder 6)
        - Great Britain, 1952-96 (Box 175, Folder 7)
        - Hong Kong, 1969-96 (Box 175, Folder 8)
        - India, 1971-94 (Box 175, Folder 9)
        - Japan, 1966-94 (Box 175, Folder 10)
        - Kenya, 1994-97 (Box 175, Folder 11)
        - Korea, 1997-98 (Box 175, Folder 12)
        - Liberia, 1971-94 (Box 175, Folder 13)
        - New Zealand, 1973-96 (Box 175, Folder 14)
        - Nigeria, 1971, 1996 (Box 175, Folder 15)
        - Palestine, 1995-96 (Box 175, Folder 16)
        - Philippines, 1972-96 (Box 175, Folder 17)
        - South Africa, 1971, 1993-96 (Box 175, Folder 18-19)
        - Sri Lanka, 1972-96 (Box 175, Folder 20)
        - Taiwan, 1971, 1996 (Box 175, Folder 21)
        - Uganda, 1993-2000 (Box 175, Folder 22)
  - Programs and Projects
    - Child Care Advocacy, 1994-97 (Box 175, Folder 23)
    - Communication and Knowledge Sharing Project: YWLink, YWNet, and Handsnet
      - YWNet/Handsnet, 1994-96 (Box 175, Folder 24)
      - Pilot evaluations, 1994-96 (Box 175, Folder 25)
      - 'Definition' Phase
        - Correspondence and presentations, 1998 (Box 175, Folder 26)
        - Final Report, 1998 (Box 175, Folder 27)
      - 'Implementation' Phase
        - Meetings, reports, 1998-99 (Box 176, Folder 1)
        - 'National Back Office': final report, Oct 1998 (Box 176, Folder 2)
        - 'Change Management': final report, Oct 1998 (Box 176, Folder 3)
        - Final Report, Dec 1998 (Box 176, Folder 4)
        - YWLink World Wide Web-based intranet system
          - Communication Plan and Communication Toolkit, 1999 (Box 176, Folder 5)
          - Training manual: draft and correspondence, Mar 1999 (Box 176, Folder 6)
          - Training Presentation, 1999 (Box 176, Folder 7)
          - "Welcome to YWLink: Guidebook and Companion Workbook," Apr 1999 (Box 176, Folder 8)
          - YWNet Notes, 1995-97 (Box 176, Folder 9)
    - Education for Global Responsibility
      - General, 1994-97 (Box 176, Folder 10)
      - Proposal, Year II, Feb 1995 (Box 176, Folder 11)
      - Reports to U.S. Agency for International Development
        - Year I, Sep 1992-Aug 1993 (Box 176, Folder 12)
        - Year II, Sep 1993-Aug 1994
          - First quarter (Box 176, Folder 13)
          - Second-Fourth quarters (Box 177, Folder 1-2)
        - Year III, Sep 1994-Aug 1995 (missing 3rd quarter) (Box 177, Folder 3)
        - Final Report, Feb 1996 (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Intervention Programs
      - Texas, 1971-73 (Box 177, Folder 5)
      - New England, 1971-77 (Box 177, Folder 6)
      - New York State, 1975-76 (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Metropolitan YWCA Consortium (proposed), 1978 (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - Race Against Racism
      - 1997-98 (Box 177, Folder 9-11)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 178, Folder 1-2)
    - Summer Youth Demonstration Project [personnel issues], 1967-68 (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - Youth Development Program, 1997-2001, n.d. (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - Week Without Violence, 1994-2001 (Box 178, Folder 5-7)
  - Public Relations
    - General (Box 178, Folder 8)
    - Corporate identity and new logo, Bass/Yager & Associates, 1986-90, n.d. (Box 178, Folder 9-10)
    - Consultants
      - Zimmerman/Edelson, Inc., 1993-96 (Box 178, Folder 11)
      - Strategy Communication Action, Ltd.
        - Communications Plan, 1994-99 (Box 178, Folder 12)
        - Communications Strategy Sessions, 1994-97 (Box 178, Folder 13)
  - Publications
    - Miscellaneous, 1995-2001 (Box 178, Folder 14)
    - Annual Report, 1994-2000 (Box 178, Folder 15)
    - Child Care guidebook, 1996-98 (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Emissaries, newsletter for former National Board members, 1994-2001 (Box 178, Folder 17)
    - General brochure, 1995-98, n.d. (Box 178, Folder 18)
  - Racial Justice
    - Miscellaneous, 1994-2001, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - National Board Consultation/Ad-hoc Work Group on Desegregation in the YWCA, 1955-56 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Reports to National Board: correspondence and research, 1957 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Interdepartmental Committee to Coordinate Work on Racial Integration,1957-58 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Racial Inclusiveness
      - General, 1958-61 (Box 179, Folder 5-6)
      - Institute for Leadership in Intergroup Relations, 1960 (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Correspondence, general, 1962-65 (Box 179, Folder 8)
      - National Board mailings, 1963 (Box 179, Folder 9)
      - Community Association correspondence and responses to mailings
        - Central region, 1963 (Box 179, Folder 10)
        - Eastern region, 1963-65 (Box 179, Folder 11-12)
        - Southern region, 1963-65 (Box 179, Folder 13-14)
        - Western region, 1963 (Box 179, Folder 15)
      - March on Washington for Freedom and Jobs, 1963 (Box 179, Folder 16)
    - Ad-hoc Committee to Review Investments and Purchasing Related to Fair Employment Practices
      - General, 1963-64 (Box 179, Folder 17)
      - Responses from corporations
        - General, A - Z, 1964 (Box 180, Folder 1-5)
        - Tidewater Oil Company, 1964 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - Eastman Kodak Company and FIGHT (Freedom, Integration, God, Honor, Today), 1964-67 (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - Affirmative Action, general, 1991-96 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Reports
    - General Secretary/Executive Director/CEO
      - 1909-14, 1931-32, 1944-53, 1955-59, 1992-98 (Box 180, Folder 9-19)
      - 2000; State of the YWCA, 1994-2000 (Box 181, Folder 1-3)
    - President of the National Board reports, 1907-14, 1996-2000 (Box 181, Folder 4-6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-70 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Operational Plan, 1991, 1995-2001 (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - "Organization for Business Administration" by Robert Heller Associates, Jul 1959 (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - Study of the operations, structure, and service of the National Board offices, by Arthur Greenleigh ("Greenleigh Report"), 1958 (Box 181, Folder 10)
  - Speeches and Statements
    - Baker, Gwendolyn Calvert, 1988-93, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Alexine Clement: Race Against Racism remarks, May 1998 (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Lerrigo, Edith: "Freedom to Move," 1969 (Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Mathai-Davis, Prema
      - Miscellaneous, 1994-98, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 14-16)
      - Affirmative Action, 1995-98 (Box 181, Folder 17)
      - Aging, 1995-98 (Box 181, Folder 18)
      - Child Care, 1995-98 (Box 182, Folder 1)
      - Domestic Violence/Violence Against Women, 1995-98 (Box 182, Folder 2)
      - Fourth World Conference on Women (Beijing, China): speech at and speeches about, 1994-99 (Box 182, Folder 3)
      - Girls and Technology, 1997-99 (Box 182, Folder 4)
      - Women's Federation for World Peace keynote address, 1995 (Box 182, Folder 5)
      - World YWCA, 1994-95 (Box 182, Folder 6)
      - YWCA Events and Programs
        - Miscellaneous, 1994-99 (Box 182, Folder 7)
        - 135th Anniversary, 1994 (Box 182, Folder 8)
        - Convention, 1994, 1996, 1998 (Box 182, Folder 9)
        - National Day of Commitment to Eliminate Racism, 1994-98 (Box 182, Folder 10)
        - Race Against Racism, 1997-99 (Box 182, Folder 11)
        - Week Without Violence, 1995-97 (Box 182, Folder 12-14)
      - YWCA Groups
        - Community and Student Associations, 1994-98 (Box 182, Folder 15-16)
        - Metropolitan Seminars, 1994-97 (Box 182, Folder 17)
        - National Student Assembly, 2000 (Box 182, Folder 18)
        - Regional Councils, 1994 (Box 182, Folder 19)
        - World Service Council, 1994-96 (Box 182, Folder 20)
    - Putnam, Glendora McIlwain, 1988, 1990 (Box 182, Folder 21)
    - Rice, Anna Virena: "The Challenge of the Present Day to the Young Women's Christian Association," World's Conference, Ceylon, 1936 (Box 182, Folder 22)
    - Simons, Savilla Millis, "Desegregation and Integration in Social Work," National Conference of Social Work, May 1956: notes and text (Box 182, Folder 23)
    - Stallard, Ann
      - "Belong-Believe-Become," Apr 1992 (Box 182, Folder 24)
      - Report to Metropolitan YWCAs, El Paso, Texas, 30 Sep 1994 (Box 182, Folder 25)
      - Stewardship Speech, YWCA 34th National Convention, 1996 (Box 182, Folder 26)
- SERIES II. BUILDINGS AND PROPERTIES
  - General, 1936-58 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Reports of the Secretary for Properties and Insurance, 1922-24 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Altamont (Millbrook, New York), 1960-63 (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Asilomar Conference Grounds (Pacific Grove, California)
    - History, 1920-93 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - Conference Grounds Committee: minutes and reports, 1914-17, 1919-28, 1945-53 (17ff) (Box 183, Folder 5-21)
    - Correspondence, 1945-66 (2 ff) (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - Real estate report, 1924 (Box 184, Folder 2-4)
    - Misc. printed materials, 1900-96 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Chautauqua Hospitality House (Chautauqua, NY), 1948, 1952 (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - Fletcher Farm (Ludlow, Vermont), 1929-30, 1992 (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Grace Dodge Hotel (Washington, DC)
    - General, 1916-72 (Box 184, Folder 8)
    - "The Grace Dodge Hotel: A Study of Purposes, Policies and Operations," Curtis, Fosdick, & Belnap, 1923 (Box 184, Folder 9-11)
  - Leadership Development Center (Phoenix, Arizona) aka Fleischmann Learning Center
    - General, 1980-82, 1990, 1996, n.d. (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Administration, n.d. (Box 185, Folder 2)
    - Committees
      - Ad-hoc Fleischmann Committee, 1979 (Box 185, Folder 3)
      - Fleischmann Project/Learning Center Committee and Arizona Task Force, 1980-81 (Box 185, Folder 4)
      - YWCA Leadership Development Center Committee, Nov 1981-83 (Box 185, Folder 5-6)
      - Committee Chair's (Elizabeth Genne) notes re conversations with Project Director (Edith Williams), 1981-82 (Box 185, Folder 7)
      - Investment Committee meeting, 13 May 1982 (Box 185, Folder 8)
    - Funding
      - Feasibility Study, 1981 (Box 185, Folder 9)
      - Fleischmann Foundation: correspondence and proposals, 1979-80 (Box 185, Folder 10)
      - Fund for the Future campaign, 1981 (Box 185, Folder 11)
      - Kresge Foundation, 1982 (Box 185, Folder 12)
    - Site selection
      - Location survey, 1980 (Box 185, Folder 13)
      - Proposals, 1980-81 (Box 185, Folder 14)
      - Opposition to siting in a non-ERA state, 1981-82 (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Architect selection, 1980-81 (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - Architectural plans, 1981 (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - Budget, 1981-82 (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - Contractor selection, 1981 (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - Name selection, 1982-83 (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - Groundbreaking, 1982 (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - Publicity, 1982 (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1982-94 (Box 186, Folder 9)
    - Dedication, 1983 (Box 186, Folder 10)
    - Dedication of Meditation Room, 1985 (Box 186, Folder 11)
    - Pamphlets and brochures, 1983-97, n.d. (Box 186, Folder 12)
    - Feasibility study: LDC expansion, 1991 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Legal documents, 1981-91 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - 10th Anniversary celebration, 1994 (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - National Board headquarters
    - 125th East 27th Street
      - General, circa 1908 (Box 187, Folder 4)
      - Office Furnishings Committee, 1908 (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - "600" (600 Lexington Avenue & "The Annex" 132/135 East 52nd St., New York City)
      - General and history, 1911-82, n.d. (Box 187, Folder 6-8)
      - Future Headquarters Committee, 1910-1912 (Box 187, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1911-48 (Box 187, Folder 10)
      - Specifications, 1911 (Box 187, Folder 11-12)
      - Contracts and work orders, 1912 (Box 187, Folder 13-18)
      - Consulting Engineers' report on 596-604 Lexington Ave., 1914 (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - 25th anniversary of dedication of building, 1937 (Box 188, Folder 2-3)
    - Air conditioning, 1962-64 (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - Sale of '600'
      - General, 1980-82 (Box 188, Folder 5-6)
      - A Celebration of the Living History of '600,' 1982 (Box 188, Folder 7)
      - Photo Memories of '600,' 1983 (Box 188, Folder 8)
      - Songs about '600,' 1982 (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - 135 West 50th Street, 1981-82 (Box 188, Folder 10-11)
  - 726 Broadway, 1983-89
    - General, 1983-89 (Box 188, Folder 12)
    - Drawing of the interior, n.d. (Box 188, Folder 13)
    - 726 Committee, 1985-86 (Box 188, Folder 14)
    - Open House guest book, 1984 (Box 188, Folder 15)
  - 350 50th Avenue (Empire State Building), 1997-2001 (Box 188, Folder 16-17)
  - National Board residence (135 East 52nd Street), 1943-82, n.d. (Box 188, Folder 18)
  - National Training School, 1912, 1935 (Box 188, Folder 19)
  - Oversize Box
    - National Board headquarters
      - Donor lists, 1911-12 (Box 189)
      - Ledger: notes and reports on building, 1911-12 (Box 189)
- SERIES III. FINANCE AND FINANCIAL DEVELOPMENT
  - Subseries A. Finance and Development
    - General and History, 1913-89 (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Department/Division
      - Charters and function descriptions, 1933-91 (Box 190, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Box 190)
        - General, 1964-82 (Box 190, Folder 3-4)
        - Mailings to Community Associations, 1971-80 (Box 190, Folder 5)
      - Minutes
        - Finance Committee, 1907-09 (Box 190, Folder 6)
        - Finance Department/Division Committee
          - 1910-20 (Box 190, Folder 7-16)
          - 1921-31 (Box 191, Folder 1-11)
        - Financing Committee, 1932-33 (Box 191, Folder 12)
        - National Support and Interpretation
          - 1933-38 (Box 191, Folder 13-18)
          - 1939-47 (Box 192, Folder 1-9)
        - National Support
          - 1948-55 (Box 192, Folder 10-17)
          - 1956-64 (Box 193, Folder 1-8)
        - Financial Resources Development, 1964-69 (Box 193, Folder 9-11)
        - Financial Resources Development Core Group, 1970-71 (Box 193, Folder 12)
        - Financial Development, 1972-86, 1991, 1996-98 (Box 193, Folder 13-14)
        - Development Staff meetings, 1997-98 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Committees
      - Advisory Council on National Support Projects/for Special Projects, 1957-62 (Box 193, Folder 16)
      - Advisory Council for Special Gifts, 1961-64 (Box 193, Folder 17)
      - Bequest Committee, 1950-69 (Box 193, Folder 18)